(AIRCRAFT DRONING)
(SIREN WAILING)
(SHOUTING IN JAPANESE)
(PEOPLE CLAMORING)
(CONTINUES SHOUTING)
(TOLLING)
(CLAMORING CONTINUES)
(GUARD SHOUTING)
(CAR ENGINE REVVING)
(SHOUTING IN JAPANESE)
(PANTING)
PRISONER 1:
Where are you going?
PRISONER 2: Help me!
PRISONER 3: Over here!
(PRISONERS CONTINUE SHOUTING)
(SHOUTING IN JAPANESE)
(GRUNTING)
Go!
That was a B-29, bub.
There's no outrunning
what's coming.
OFFICER: Yashida!
(SHOUTING IN JAPANESE)
You're better
off down here.
(SPEAKING JAPANESE)
I'd hurry
if I were you.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(BLADE UNSHEATHES)
(GROANS)
(BOTH GROANING)
(GASPS)
(HIGH-PITCHED WHINING)
Run. Now!
(YASHIDA SHOUTS)
Stay down!
(STRAINING)
(LOGAN GRUNTS)
(GASPING)
(WHEEZING)
(GRUNTING)
(GROANS LOUDLY)
No, wait!
No, no. Wait.
No. It's not safe.
JEAN GREY: Wake up, wake up,
wake up. Wake up.
(PANTING)
Where were you?
Nagasaki.
That far back?
(KISSES)
You're here.
Of course.
Can you stay?
You know I can't.
Jean, I'm so sorry.
I know.
I'll never hurt you
or anyone ever again.
I made a vow.
A solemn vow?
You're making fun of me.
It's too late.
No! No, Jean!
No, no, no! Please!
You can't hide.
You can't hide!
No, Jean! No!
No.
(GASPING)
(CLASSICAL MUSIC
PLAYING ON RADIO)
(SIGHS)
(RADIO STATIC)
(GROWLING)
(SIX FEET UNDER
PLAYING ON STEREO)
(MEN TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
Whack all of that
on store credit.
Thanks, honey.
Got the arrows?
Yeah.
(CAR HORN HONKING)
EDDIE: Remember the arrows?
Yeah, yeah, Eddie,
we got them!
(SIX FEET UNDER
CONTINUES PLAYING)
Yeah!
(MEN WHOOPING)
(GUNSHOT)
(MAN 1 GROANS)
MAN 2: Hey!
What are you doing?
Man, you almost
blew his foot off!
You're not a hunter,
are you?
Not anymore.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(MAN SCREAMS)
(GUNSHOT)
(DOG BARKING)
(BEAR GROWLING)
What the hell?
(ROARS)
(WHIMPERING)
Don't make me do this.
(ROARING)
(LOW PLAYING)
It must have been
damn near 12 feet tall.
We didn't hear
nothing except twigs.
Then it just
came upon us.
It got Riley,
just gutted him.
It got Eddie.
Ripped through the tent,
knocked over the snowcat
like it was a toy.
You the one was attacked
by the grizzly?
I'm the one
that survived.
I'd like to buy
this man a drink.
What's your name,
mister?
(GROANS)
It's Logan.
And that's a poison
broadhead, which,
last I heard, was illegal.
(GLASS SHATTERING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(GROANING)
Go ahead,
ask me where I found it.
(GROANING LOUDLY)
Ask me.
Where did you find it?
Well,
funny you should ask.
I pulled it out of
the back of a grizzly.
Whoever shot it,
didn't have the wind
or the balls
to track
the animal properly...
and put it out
of its misery.
(GROANS)
Instead of dropping
a lethal dose
of the poison...
it bled into the bear,
made him crazy,
killed five people.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Because I don't dip
my arrows in anything.
In that case,
you got nothing
to worry about.
(GRUNTS)
Damn.
That hurt.
(GLASS CLATTERS)
Sorry, Jean.
I wouldn't
bother with them.
Most of them will
die soon anyway,
without your help.
Three of them,
a week from now
in the same truck.
(GRUNTS)
(COUGHING)
This sword is
hundreds of years old...
and was named Danzan
by the first samurai
who used it.
Danzan means
"separator"
in Japanese.
The ideal weapon
for separating head
and limb from body.
Whoa!
Like so.
(GLASS CLATTERING)
I'm parked in back.
Get in.
(ENGINE STARTS)
(POLICE SIREN WAILING)
Sorry, it's a rental.
Who are you?
Me? I'm Yukio.
And?
I've been trying
to find you
for over a year.
Why?
To give you that.
My employer
wanted you to have it.
Who's your employer?
Master Yashida.
He said it belongs
to you, and that
he's paying all debts.
Master Yashida is dying.
He wants to say thank you
for saving his life
all those years ago.
He knows that
you are a...
busy man.
But he very much
wants to say his
goodbye in person.
All right,
where is he?
Tokyo.
Wait...
I'm not going to Japan.
It would be
dishonorable for you
to refuse his request.
Well, apologize
to Mr. Yashida,
I'm not going to Tokyo.
All right?
I've got things to do.
Do not apologize.
It's been an honor
just to meet
the Wolverine.
That's not
who I am anymore,
you understand?
Interesting.
Why did you go
into that bar,
if not to seek justice?
I don't know.
You don't know.
No!
I think you know.
Pull over.
You are a soldier.
No, I'm not.
Pull over.
You are a soldier.
Pull over, now!
Now.
(BRAKES SCREECH)
You are a soldier,
and you seek what
all soldiers do.
And what's that?
An honorable death.
An end to your pain.
Who says I'm in pain?
A man who has nightmares
every night of his life
is in pain.
One day.
I say goodbye
to Mr. Yashida and
I come right back.
Okay.
Fifteen hours.
Depending on the wind.
Fifteen hours?
You don't like to fly?
I love it.
(EXHALES)
(SIGHS)
YOUNG YASHIDA:
Kuzuri.
What does that mean?
Monster.
No pain?
You have no...
Oh, yeah. Pain.
Plenty of pain.
How old are you?
It's been
a long time.
Many wars.
Understand?
(SIGHS)
Too many
fuckin' wars.
(EXHALES)
We are almost there.
So, you can
see the future?
I can read a map.
You said you knew
the future of those
assholes in the bar.
I know
they are going to die.
We are all going to die.
You said they would
die in the same truck,
in a week.
If you're right,
that's quite a talent.
We don't all have claws.
(SIGHS)
So, do I die
on this plane?
No.
Not on this plane.
(FEMALE ANNOUNCER
SPEAKING JAPANESE ON SPEAKER)
YUKIO: Don't let
the lights fool you.
These are dark days
in Japan.
Some believe
when Master Yashida
got sick,
a shadow fell upon us.
Do you think
he's a god?
No. A man.
But a great one.
After the war,
he helped rebuild
the nation.
And the family business
became Japan's largest.
Wow. Did they
give you a little
card to memorize?
I owe Master Yashida
my life.
Don't be a dick.
(RADIO CHATTER)
A lot of guns.
There have been attacks.
Attempted kidnappings.
Attempted assassinations.
By who?
The Japanese mob,
the Yakuza.
They've grown strong
as the government
has grown weak.
(ALARM BEEPING)
(ALL SPEAKING JAPANESE)
Hip replacement.
(SPEAKING JAPANESE)
Uh, too small.
Too small.
(MEN GRUNTING)
Hey.
This way.
Who's that?
Shingen,
Master Yashida's son.
He's good.
He's all right.
(BOTH GREETING IN JAPANESE)
So, what happened
to the badass in boots?
Master Yashida
is traditional.
One eye on the past
and the other on the future.
(DOOR LOCK BEEPS)
(YASHIDA SPEAKING
SOFTLY IN JAPANESE)
(SPEAKING JAPANESE)
That's Mariko,
his granddaughter.
(GLASS CLATTERING)
Mariko.
(SPEAKING JAPANESE)
What's wrong with you?
(SOBBING)
You haven't answered my emails.
I can't tell you now.
Yes, you can.
Who is the caveman?
The man Grandfather wanted me to find.
You can't bring him in like that.
Shizu and Saki
are going to
disinfect you.
Give you a shave.
Like hell they are.
Get in the tub.
(SIGHS)
Whoa.
Get in the tub.
Really?
(WOMEN SHOUTING
IN JAPANESE)
All right.
Okay. Okay.
All right,
all right, all right.
I can do that bit.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
What?
You look nice.
I feel violated.
DR. GREEN: Prepare
two more suppressors
for Master Yashida.
And check
his blood pressure.
Yashida-sama.
(SPEAKING JAPANESE)
Oh...
Kuzuri.
You look the same.
But, then,
that is no surprise.
Dr. Green.
Leave us, please.
Five minutes,
no more.
My oncologist.
Well done.
Oh, forget the etiquette.
I'm past such precautions.
(EXHALES)
For many years
I have wanted to thank you
for saving my life.
Yeah, well...
You were kind to me.
And you were kind
to many people.
I saw that even
from that well.
(GROANS SOFTLY)
(EXHALES)
YASHIDA: The painting
is from the village
of my birth.
It depicts
the bravery and skill
of the Black Clan.
Ninja warriors.
They served my family
for seven centuries.
I didn't send for you
only to thank you, Logan.
I wanted to repay you.
To offer you something
no one else can.
A gift to equal
the life you gave to me.
I don't need anything.
Not a thing.
Eternity can be a curse.
It hasn't been
easy for you,
living without time.
The losses you
have had to suffer.
A man can run out
of things to live for.
Lose his purpose.
Become a ronin.
A samurai without a master.
I can end your eternity.
Make you mortal.
What they did to me,
what I am, can't be undone.
Yashida Industries
can do anything.
We have reason
to believe your ability
to heal can be passed.
Passed?
From you to another.
(SIGHS)
You have struggled
long enough, Logan.
I'm confused.
I came here to say goodbye
to a man I once knew.
I am the same man.
I was not ready
to die then.
I am not ready
to die now.
But you are...
aren't you?
Are you offering to kill me?
No.
Not right away.
You can live a long
and ordinary life.
Fall in love,
have a family...
grow old.
And one day,
die an ordinary death.
It can be done.
Yeah, look,
nice to see you again.
Sorry you got sick.
Please, Logan-san.
I need you again.
I fear for my family.
(HEART MONITOR
BEEPING RAPIDLY)
I fear for everything
I have built.
Enough.
You should leave.
Please, Logan-san.
They're going
to kill her.
Who?
Mariko, my granddaughter.
She is my treasure.
She must be protected.
You don't want
what I've got.
(MONITOR CONTINUES
BEEPING RAPIDLY)
Kuzuri.
Kuzuri!
(SPEAKING JAPANESE)
Lord Shingen, your father is asking for you.
It is time.
(MARIKO SPEAKING JAPANESE)
I need to speak with my father...
before he speaks to Grandfather.
He'll talk to you later, Mariko.
Father! I need to see you now!
Not now, Mariko!
(SHINGEN AND MARIKO
ARGUING IN JAPANESE)
(MEN SHOUTING IN JAPANESE)
(GASPING)
Careful, careful.
It's slippery out here.
Let go.
(PANTING)
You about done?
Let go of me.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
He just wanted
to say goodbye, huh?
You two
grew up together.
Yes.
But you're not
her sister.
No.
Master Yashida found me
on a trip to the South.
He brought Mariko
to see a factory
he was building.
I was digging
through the garbage
for something to eat.
So they just took
you home with them?
It was always
difficult for Mariko
to make friends.
I'll see to it the plane
is ready in the morning.
Sleep here.
(SPEAKING JAPANESE)
Don't look so sad, Shingen.
I'm still dying.
I'll be in my office
if you need me.
(SPEAKING JAPANESE)
There is no easy way to say this.
But then, it's never been easy for us, has it?
I have tried, father.
You've done the best you can.
You have always been
my assumed successor.
So the past few years,
as a test,
I allowed you
more control.
It has been an honor.
And I now realize
that was a mistake.
You have brought
this company
close to ruin.
(SPEAKING JAPANESE)
When I die,
someone else will take
my place as chairman.
Father,
I'm sorry if I have
disappointed you...
Let's not insult
one another.
You are not the man
to lead Yashida.
You cannot bring in
someone from the outside.
In that,
you are correct.
(SNICKERS)
(LAUGHS INCREDULOUSLY)
(SPEAKING JAPANESE)
That will never happen.
(HEART MONITOR
BEEPING RAPIDLY)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
YASHIDA: Eternity
can be a curse...
Kuzuri.
YOUNG YASHIDA:
You have no pain, Kuzuri?
How old are you?
JEAN GREY: Interesting offer.
What are you doing
turning the old man down?
I thought you
wanted to be with me.
Come here.
(GRUNTS)
(GAGGING)
(GASPING)
(SHOUTS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(WOMAN SOBBING)
(FOOTSTEPS RETREATING)
(WOMAN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
(MEN SPEAKING JAPANESE)
YUKIO: He's dead.
I didn't foresee it.
(CAMERAS CLICKING)
(BOTH SPEAKING JAPANESE)
(GUARDS CHATTERING
INDISTINCTLY)
(ALL CHANTING)
Who's that?
With Mariko.
His name is Noburo Mori.
Minister of Justice,
a rising star.
He's Mariko's fiancé.
You need to bow.
(WHISPERS)
Bow.
(CLEARS THROAT)
YUKIO: Lord Shingen,
this is Mr. Logan.
I know who he is.
Your father
was a good man.
(SCOFFS)
He would often say
the same about you.
But then, he was always
fascinated with your kind.
Tell me, why do you
think he sent our
little Yukio to fetch you?
To say goodbye.
And now you have.
Time for you to go
back to your cave.
(GONG BANGING)
Anyone else
you want me to meet?
(SPEAKING JAPANESE)
I pledge to you...
Master Yashida...
to be vigilant...
and to dedicate my life...
to protect Mariko.
YUKIO: That armor belonged
to Shiruba-Samurai...
the Silver Samurai.
It will stand watch
over the old man forever.
Logan?
Hey.
Something's not right.
Let go.
(GUARD SPEAKING JAPANESE)
(SHOUTS IN JAPANESE)
(SHOUTING CONTINUES)
(YELLS)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
(EXHALES)
(YELLS)
Logan!
(GUNFIRE)
(GROANING)
(YELLING)
(SPEAKING JAPANESE)
(GRUNTS)
(PEOPLE CONTINUE SCREAMING)
(GUNFIRE)
(GRUNTS)
Logan!
(GASPING)
(MAN SHOUTING IN JAPANESE)
(SCREAMS)
(GROANS)
(GRUNTS)
(SCREAMS)
(GUNFIRE)
(PANTING)
(SPEAKING JAPANESE)
(GRUNTING)
(MEN SHOUTING IN JAPANESE)
(GROANS)
Kuzuri.
Let's go.
Come on, let's go!
Yukio!
Mariko!
(SPEAKS JAPANESE)
(GUNSHOTS)
(METAL CLANGING)
(GROANS)
Mariko!
(MEN SHOUTING)
(CAR HORN BLARING)
(WOMAN SCREAMS)
(MEN SHOUTING IN JAPANESE)
Come on.
Let's go, let's go.
(GUNSHOTS)
(WOMAN SCREAMS)
(GROANS)
(YELLING)
(GUNFIRE CONTINUES)
Here, here! Here!
(LIVELY SLOT MACHINE
MUSIC PLAYING)
(GROANS)
Move!
In here! Move!
(GUNFIRE)
(MAN SHOUTING IN JAPANESE)
(BANGS)
(GRUNTS)
(BOTH PANTING)
(CHOKING)
Keep moving,
keep moving.
Move!
(PEOPLE CLAMORING)
(POLICE SIREN WAILING)
You're bleeding.
You need help.
Just keep moving.
(PANTING)
(WOMAN CHATTERING ON PA)
Thank you for
what you did back there.
Those were Yakuza.
I'm fine.
Why are they after you?
I'm fine. I can make
my way from here.
You should go.
Get yourself a doctor.
(MEN SPEAKING JAPANESE)
(BELL CHIMES)
(MAN CHATTERING ON PA)
(CLATTERS)
Whoa!
(CHUCKLES)
That's nice.
This is one of those
bullet trains, right?
I told you I don't
need your help.
So what do they do,
like, 300 miles an hour?
(AMBULANCE SIREN WAILING)
(CAMERAS CLICKING)
(REPORTERS CLAMORING)
(SPEAKING JAPANESE)
This cowardly attack was...
the work of Yakuza thugs.
A violent response to my efforts...
to crack down on organized crime.
They exited the North Gate.
She was with the stranger...
Your gaijin friend,
where is he?
Last I saw,
he was protecting
your daughter.
(SCOFFS)
You are a toy doll.
A companion for a child
who has outgrown you.
Keep that in mind.
(SPEAKS JAPANESE)
So, where are we
headed, Mariko?
Where are we going?
I'm going to the end
of the line.
My family has a home
in the South.
That's stupid.
No offense,
but they're gonna know
to look for you there.
Not this place.
You want
to be left alone.
Yes.
I understand.
Do you?
Oh, yeah.
Trust me.
Problem is,
if I do that...
I don't think you're
gonna live to see
the end of the day.
You can't pretend
shit isn't happening
when it is, princess.
Unless you want to die.
In that case, you're
playing this perfectly.
(GROANS)
(SIGHS)
Oh... What the hell?
(GROANS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Oh...
What the hell is happening?
(MEN SPEAKING JAPANESE)
(YELLS)
(ALL GRUNTING)
(WIND HOWLING)
(SCREAMING)
(YELLS)
(YELLING)
(SCREAMS)
(GASPS)
(MUSIC PLAYING
ON HEADPHONES)
(YELLING)
(SCREAMING)
(WOMAN CHATTERING ON PA)
(PANTING)
What happened to you?
We get off here.
Let's go.
Just listen to me,
will you? We need
to find someplace safe.
I don't understand.
How do you know
they were Yakuza?
They were the same
guys from the temple.
How do you know
they were after me?
Look, we need to
find someplace safe.
We need to get
off the streets.
I don't understand.
Shut up! Listen.
Do you know this place?
Where's downtown?
Straight ahead.
So, where's
the nice part of town?
Another eight blocks
that way.
Good.
We're staying here.
Let's go.
This is a love hotel.
A what?
A love hotel.
For couples,
understand?
Uh... Right.
Hey.
Uh, two rooms.
Adjoining rooms,
on the same floor.
(SPEAKING JAPANESE)
Right next to each other.
Very close.
Same floor. Same floor.
(SIGHS)
(SPEAKING JAPANESE)
What did she say?
She has no rooms
available next
to each other.
She's asking if we prefer
"the dungeon",
"the nurse's office..."
Or the "mission to Mars."
(WOMAN GIGGLING)
(BED CREAKING)
This'll do.
MAN ON SPEAKERS:
Liftoff! We have a liftoff!
Kind of homey,
actually.
Where do you plan
on sleeping?
I don't.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(SHATTERS)
JEAN GREY:
That's a lot of blood.
I thought you were
done being the hero.
But these guys were...
trying to kill her.
Just let it go.
It's not hard to die.
Come to me.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(MEN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
Eh!
Oh.
JEAN GREY: Logan...
You're slipping.
(GRUNTS)
(SHOUTING IN JAPANESE)
(GROANS)
(ZAPPING)
(GASPS)
(LAUGHING)
(GROANS)
(SHOUTS IN JAPANESE)
(GRUNTS)
JEAN GREY: Logan...
(TASER CRACKLING)
(MAN 1 SPEAKING JAPANESE)
Kill him already!
Wanna say something
before you die, gaijin?
(MAN 2 SCREAMS)
(MAN 1 SPEAKING JAPANESE)
(GRUNTS)
(ZAPPING)
(EXCLAIMING IN PAIN)
(GROANING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(GOAT BLEATING)
(MACHINE WHIRRING)
(PEOPLE WHISPERING
IN JAPANESE)
(MAN SHUSHING)
(BULLETS CLATTERING)
(SPEAKS JAPANESE)
(GRUNTS)
This is Mieko from the hotel
and her grandson, Hitoshi.
Is he a doctor?
In a manner
of speaking, yes.
He's a veterinarian...
student.
Large animal.
(BIRD CHIRPING)
Uh... Thanks.
(GASPS)
(INSTRUMENTS CLATTERING)
Whoa.
You may have cut him
once or twice while
he was stitching you.
Okay, okay, okay.
(SPEAKING JAPANESE)
Hey.
Thank you.
I never needed
this before.
What? Help?
That doctor,
the one who helped your
grandfather, the blonde.
Who is she?
He met her last year
when he was in America
for treatment.
Your grandfather
told me my healing
could be taken from me,
passed on.
I'm not getting better,
not like before.
She did this to me.
MAN: Blondie!
(MAN SPEAKING JAPANESE)
Blondie!
How much?
How much, yeah?
(PEOPLE GASPING)
You kept me
waiting two hours.
You have no respect.
So you haven't
found them?
Don't play with me, bitch.
I could kill you.
If you could make me
feel something, Harada,
that would be sublime.
I can slit your
pretty mouth open,
before you open it to
say one more stupid...
Ah...
I asked you to do
one thing, little man.
Bring me the mutant.
I don't work for you.
I work for the House of...
(BLOWING AIR)
(GASPING)
You work for Yashida,
I get it.
Yet you cannot
fulfill his dying wish.
My God, if you had
any idea how much
you have failed him.
Where is Logan?
I am not done with him.
(GASPING)
The mutant has powers.
(GRUNTS)
He's just a man now.
His flesh is weak now.
I did that.
I suppressed his power
so he could be taken.
You see, it's me
you should respect.
(GRUNTS)
Just find them,
before the Yakuza.
(MUTTERING)
(GRUNTS)
We get off here.
Where are we?
Just outside Nagasaki.
This way.
This is the guy from
the funeral, the archer.
He was your boyfriend.
That's Harada.
We were village
champions that summer.
He with the bow
and me with the knives.
Harada and I were
planning to get married.
What stopped you?
Grandfather.
He said we had to wait
until we were at least 15.
From the mountain,
from the sea.
(BOTH SPEAKING JAPANESE)
(SIGHS)
Chopsticks upright
are a bad omen.
It resembles incense
at a funeral.
Nothing is without meaning.
So, the other night
at the house,
when you ran out
in the rain...
what did that mean?
My grandfather was dying.
You knew he was gonna die.
He'd been sick
for a long time.
It wasn't
his death I feared.
So, what, then?
What did he tell
you that night?
Mariko, why did
your father hit you?
I was trying
to warn him.
About what?
What did your
grandfather tell you?
He told me that...
in three days,
when they read
his will...
I will become
the most powerful
person in Japan.
He gave it all to me.
The company?
I didn't want it.
He knew that.
I don't understand
why he gave it to me.
It was all my father
dreamed of.
Well, that's why.
What about this
fiancé of yours?
Nostromo.
Noburo.
Does he know
about this?
No.
Why are you
marrying him?
He seems like
kind of an asshole.
My father arranged it
last year.
What?
It gives him a better access
to the political theater.
To disobey my father
would be to dishonor him.
I don't expect
you to understand.
You're not Japanese.
(SHINGEN SPEAKING JAPANESE)
Our island is long and thin.
Trains only run in two directions.
I assure you Lord Shingen...
my officers are making every effort...
Then they're idiots.
You've wasted enough of my time.
I have my father's affairs to attend to.
Get out and find her!
Tell me you have
more promising news
from your contacts.
They open the will
in three days.
We are running
out of time.
Soon, I hope.
I'm sending men
to the South.
That's where
we found the bodies.
(YUKIO SPEAKING
JAPANESE ON PHONE)
If the Yakuza got into the funeral...
they had someone inside.
They'll never find me here.
You're not safe.
I'm coming down there.
They'll follow you.
Please.
Wait a few days.
Please. I'm fine.
Logan's here.
He's wounded, Mariko.
(WOMAN SPEAKING JAPANESE)
Someone's here.
LOGAN: Mariko?
I have to go.
Mariko?
(WOMAN SPEAKING JAPANESE)
A tree fell on the road.
The men could use some help.
(ALL SPEAKING JAPANESE)
(GRUNTING)
(EXHALES)
Are you okay?
Tired.
Do you need something?
No.
(BOTH GREETING IN JAPANESE)
This will help.
(AIRPLANE APPROACHING)
It's time.
What?
Please. Take it.
Thank you.
No.
Two hands.
Japanese sword
require two hands.
Like that?
That's it.
It's beautiful,
Yashida.
But I can't take it.
Please.
Thank you.
Keep it safe.
Keep it safe for me.
Someday,
I'll come get it.
It's time.
(GASPING)
(SOBBING)
I was here
when it happened.
It's how I met
your grandfather.
We hid in there.
I heard the stories.
My grandfather would say...
what happened here
was proof that everything
in the world finds peace.
Eventually.
That man can
recover from anything.
Maybe you, too.
You don't sleep very well.
You call out
in the night.
Who's Jean?
We should go back.
There's rain coming.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
I'll make tea.
For you.
(SIGHS)
This isn't right.
You need this tied
like a proper samurai.
Your grandfather
called me a ronin.
A samurai
without a master.
He said
I was destined
to live forever...
with no reason to live.
Was he right?
Yes.
Still?
Hey.
What are you doing?
This isn't going
to end well.
Everyone you love dies.
(BLADE UNSHEATHES)
(GRUNTS)
(GASPS)
(PANTING)
(YELLS)
Kuzuri.
Do you know
what that means?
An animal.
A fierce creature
with long claws
and sharp teeth.
It fears nothing.
When I was a girl,
I had nightmares.
I'd wake up and
run to my parents.
My father
would get angry.
(SPEAKING JAPANESE)
"Go back to sleep.
Face your fears."
My grandfather
was different.
He told me stories
about Kuzuri, his friend.
Who he met at the bottom
of a well.
He said the Kuzuri
was magical and
saved his life.
He said Kuzuri
would protect me, too,
as I slept in my bed.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Who's Jean?
Is she like you?
What happened to her?
She died.
I killed her.
Along with the Kuzuri.
Logan.
Mariko?
MARIKO: Logan!
(MAN SHOUTING)
Logan!
Mariko?
Mariko!
MARIKO: No! Logan!
No!
Logan!
(GRUNTS)
Mariko!
MARIKO: Logan!
No!
Logan!
Mariko! Mariko!
(GRUNTING)
Where are they
taking her?
Where, you piece of shit?
I no talk, gaijin.
I never talk.
(MAN GROANS)
Who hired you?
Uh-oh.
Take me to Noburo.
Logan...
Take me to him.
I need to tell
you something.
Do it. Now.
You wait in the car.
Logan.
What?
I saw you die.
When? Just now?
A while ago.
But it's not like
I get a complete picture.
More like looking
through a keyhole.
But I'm always right.
All I can see
is one part of
a person's life...
their death.
And I saw yours.
So, what did you see?
I see you on your back.
There's blood everywhere.
You're holding
your own heart
in your hand.
It's not beating.
I don't have time
for this shit.
When I was five,
I knew how my own
parents would die.
Then I watched it happen
from the back seat.
Look at me.
A lot of people
have tried to kill me,
and I'm still here.
Yeah...
but you're
different now,
aren't you?
They can hurt you.
They can kill you.
Just wait in the car.
I said, wait in the car.
You need backup.
You're not safe,
not in your condition.
Just think of me
as your bodyguard.
(SIGHS)
(SLOW MUSIC PLAYING)
(NOBURO CHUCKLING)
WOMAN: Sexy.
(NOBURO LAUGHS)
NOBURO: Come on!
WOMAN: I'm coming.
(SPEAKING JAPANESE)
(ALL LAUGHING)
WOMAN: Okay, round four.
Here we go.
(NOBURO SPEAKING JAPANESE)
WOMAN: Drink for you,
my lady.
(BOTH SHRIEKING)
Get out.
(MUSIC STOPS)
Not you.
Call me old-fashioned...
but I thought
being engaged meant
you were done
with this kind
of bullshit.
I am the Minister
of Justice.
Do you have any idea
what I could do to you?
Really? You're gonna
try and talk tough,
standing there in
your red underwear?
You have ten words...
ten words...
to explain to me why you,
the Minister of Justice...
would want your fiancé
killed by the Yakuza.
And if I don't
like what you say,
you are going through
that fucking window.
You don't have
the faintest idea
what's going on...
(GROANS)
How many words was that?
Nine.
You have one word left.
Really?
(GRUNTS)
Shingen. Shingen!
Keep going.
Since he got sick...
old man Yashida
spent billions
on doctors, healers.
Stockpiling adamantium
at his lab in the North...
secretly trying
to prolong his life.
He brought the company
to the edge of bankruptcy.
He was obsessed
with you.
(SPEAKING JAPANESE)
(GROANS)
English!
Shingen lied,
protected the old man...
concealed the debt
from stockholders
and the board.
He tried to be a good son
and thought he'd be rewarded.
And then the old man
left everything to
his granddaughter.
If Mariko got all that power,
she would dump his ass.
It's true.
Mariko would have
never gone through
with the wedding...
not once the will
was revealed.
She never took to me.
Oh, really?
A class act like you.
Shingen promised me
a fortune for my help.
So, you put a hit
on his daughter.
Is that it?
Political careers
don't last forever.
That's right.
Wait! Wait! No!
You wanted the truth.
I told you the truth!
I didn't like it.
Wow.
How did you know
there's a pool
down there?
I didn't.
(SPEAKS JAPANESE)
Did you know I studied biology in college?
Genetics.
There are genes that skip generations.
Recessive genes.
Eyes.
Eyes. Hair.
Talent.
Temperament.
Not every child gets the same.
My father saw little of himself in me.
But in you...
he faced a mirror.
How did you convince my father...
to award you control...
of Asia's largest corporation?
You've gone insane.
I'm just waking up.
If you kill me, you will lose...
what little honor you have left.
Fear not Mariko.
I don't want to hurt you.
I want to help you.
Help you end your pain...
what that mutant stopped you...
from doing last week.
I never wanted to die, Father.
(GASPS)
(SPEAKING JAPANESE)
(HARADA SPEAKING JAPANESE)
It's alright, Mariko.
(GASPING)
Come with me.
What is happening?!
More than you can imagine.
You.
Me.
Sorry to interrupt,
but I need your
daughter alive.
What are you?
A chemist, a nihilist...
a capitalist,
a mutation.
A viper.
(CHOKES)
(GROANS)
(YELLS)
Where is
the security?
Yakuza.
Shingen?
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Logan.
This. This here.
Where is this?
Master Yashida's
birthplace.
The company
built a facility
into the mountainside.
How far?
500 kilometers from here.
(BEEPS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(GRUNTS)
(ELECTRONIC WHIRRING)
I gotta get that
thing out of me.
How?
No, stop, Logan.
I saw you die.
I'm never wrong.
You're not always right.
You didn't know
the old man was
gonna bite it.
I saw you die in a room
like this with your heart
in your hand.
I can't leave her with
those freaks and killers.
I'm the only chance
she's got, but not with
that thing inside me.
You're going to die, Logan.
Maybe that's okay.
(GROANS)
No, listen to me, Logan!
No, stop. Logan!
You're not gonna want
to watch this part.
(GROANING)
No! Listen to me!
Please, no!
No, stop.
Listen to me.
Logan!
(SNIGGERS)
Move!
(YELLS)
Stay away from him.
(LOGAN SCREAMING)
He killed your master.
Put hands on your sister.
And now you want him?
(ALARM BLARING)
Oh, no. I can't see.
You'll always
be a beggar.
You're crazy.
LOGAN: Oh, no.
(BOTH GRUNT)
(GROANING)
(GASPING)
(GRUNTING)
(BEEPING)
Yukio.
(GROANING)
(EXHALES)
(HEART MONITOR FLATLINING)
Logan!
(YUKIO YELLING)
Logan! Logan!
Logan!
Don't hit my friends.
Where's Mariko?
She's gone.
That Viper bitch
took her.
It was my father's
obsession...
with mutation,
with God's mistakes...
like you and her,
that ruined this house.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
You tried to kill
your daughter.
Live with that.
(YELLING)
What kind
of monster are you?
The Wolverine.
Hey, come here,
come here. That's it.
I was wrong.
I told you.
Let me have
a look at you.
It's nothing.
Hey, thank you.
It's a trap, Logan.
(MARIKO SPEAKING JAPANESE)
Why have you brought me here?
What are you hiding?
You will soon find out.
Welcome, Mariko.
It's all right, Mariko.
She also serves
the House of Yashida.
MARIKO:
She serves herself.
She infected Logan.
Hmm...
And what about
Grandfather?
What did you
infect him with?
I granted
his dying wish.
I helped him rest.
Now, it's your turn.
(GASPS)
(SPEAKING JAPANESE)
Listen to me, mutant.
She will not be harmed.
She will be fine.
So long as you do your job.
Logan will be here soon,
you should prepare.
It was easy
to lure him here.
It's another thing
to capture him.
We're ready.
He's never faced
the Black Clan.
Yes, well...
Dip your arrows in this.
It won't kill him,
but it will slow him down.
Keep your potions.
He's no challenge
for us now. He's weak.
Okay.
But when you fail...
you have this.
VIPER: Did you have
a nice rest?
I don't know
what you said or did
to deceive Harada
or my grandfather...
Now, now, calm down.
Your grandfather
sought me out.
I am the head
of this family now.
And why do you
suppose that is?
Why do you think
the old man chose you?
Because you are strong?
Or because you are weak?
I see you've
come to fight.
It's pointless.
You're weak.
You're outnumbered.
The Black Clan
has protected the House
of Yashida for 700 years.
Is that all the men
you brought?
I'm gonna get her.
We are grateful
for your protection
of Mariko.
But there is one more
sacrifice you must
make for her family.
Go fuck yourself,
pretty boy.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(SHOUTING IN JAPANESE)
(MEN SHOUTING)
(STARTS ENGINE)
(GRUNTS)
(SCREAMS)
(PANTING)
Yukio, run!
(SPITS)
(YELLS)
(NINJAS SCREAMING)
(GROANING)
(MEN SHOUTING)
Logan.
(GROANING)
(GROANS)
KAYLA: Logan.
LOGAN: Kayla.
I love you.
Kayla!
Logan.
(LOGAN GROANS)
MARIKO: Logan!
LOGAN: Mariko!
Jean.
JEAN GREY: Save me.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(GRUNTING)
(GRUNTS)
(PANTING)
Stand back.
There is no need.
Where is she?
Where's Mariko?
"Where is Mariko?"
Still pining away?
That's so sweet.
Impressive, no?
He is made of adamantium,
just like you.
(GRUNTS)
Oh, Logan,
you know what, I get it.
You're frustrated.
I know she's here.
I want to see her.
You want answers.
Yes, I want answers!
I'm sorry,
I wish I could say more,
but I was hired in
part for my discretion.
I'm sure you were.
That...
and a certain talent
for combining biochemistry
and metaphysics.
High-grade toxins
are my specialty.
It helps to be
genetically immune
to every poison
known to man, as I am.
And immune to the toxin
that is man himself...
as I am.
I'll tell you what,
you twisted mutant bitch...
why don't you
open these bracelets
and we'll see
who's made of what?
(GRUNTING)
The claws.
Now we can begin.
(GROANING)
(HARADA SPEAKING JAPANESE)
I know you care for him.
You need to let go of that.
You are a Yashida.
She betrayed my grandfather...
and so have you.
No Mariko.
We grew up together.
You need to trust me.
Let me go to him!
He saved my life!
Let him go, Mariko!
This isn't easy for me but...
I'm following Grandfather's wishes.
The suppressant bug
you found inside
of you was mine.
You took it out
on your own.
I didn't see that coming.
The Viper woman is evil...
we both know that.
But she's a means to an end...
LOGAN: (GRUNTS)
Where is she?
An end your grandfather wanted.
VIPER: You are strong.
You have courage.
Real courage.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
But that won't
help much now.
What the...?
You need to trust me.
Is that hard?
We were meant to be together.
We still can be.
Perhaps.
(GROANING)
(PANTING)
MARIKO: Stop!
(BOTH GRUNTING)
This is madness.
Let's go.
Go!
Run!
(SNARLING)
(CHOKES)
Come on.
Mariko, come!
Go! Run!
(GRUNTING)
(GROANING)
Mariko, get out!
(GRUNTING)
(SNARLS)
(SCREAMING)
(GROANING)
(SCREAMS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Ahhh!
(GROANS)
(PANTING)
(GROANING)
(YELLING)
(GROANS)
(HARADA SHOUTING)
Come on.
This is not the way.
(GASPING)
Two hands.
Master...
Hey! Bub!
(GRUNTS)
(SCREAMS)
(GRUNTING)
MARIKO: Harada.
(SPEAKING JAPANESE)
I'm sorry.
(GASPING)
(LOGAN GRUNTING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(SCREAMING)
(YUKIO YELLING)
(BOTH PANTING)
Now, you die.
Today is not my day.
(CABLES WHIRRING)
(GROANING)
(YELLING)
(GRUNTING)
(GROANING)
Hey!
Logan-san.
Don't look so shocked.
With you at my side,
I survived Nagasaki.
Surely,
I could survive this.
It's all right.
It won't take long.
Dr. Green and I
have been waiting.
(GROANING LOUDLY)
It's only this armor
that's kept me alive.
We built it to make me
strong, so I can take
what you would not give.
And transfer your
unwanted healing...
to my body.
My legacy must
be preserved.
Your mistake was to believe
that a life without end...
can have no meaning.
It is the only
life that can.
Hold on.
We are almost there.
The peace,
the peace you've wanted.
Your reward.
You know,
I'm giving you
the very death...
you longed for.
(CHUCKLES)
(INHALES)
This feeling...
to be invincible...
like you.
(MARIKO GRUNTS)
(GASPS)
(SPEAKING JAPANESE)
You are a monster.
Mariko.
It's me.
Your grandfather.
I buried my grandfather.
(GROANS)
(PANTING)
(GRUNTING)
(ARMOR SHORT-CIRCUITING)
(YELLING)
(GROANS)
You asked me to
come say goodbye.
Sayonara.
(SCREAMING)
(CRASHING)
(PANTING)
Are you all right?
Logan.
JEAN GREY:
(WHISPERING) Logan.
Logan.
You're here.
Of course.
Can you stay?
I can't.
Yes, you can.
This is what you wanted.
Not anymore.
I'm all alone here.
You put me here.
You were hurting
people, Jean.
I had to.
I love you, Jean.
I always will.
(SPEAKING JAPANESE)
You are my only family.
Be well, sister.
Am I wrong to think
you might visit me soon?
Stay.
I can't, princess.
I'm a soldier,
and I've been
hiding too long.
MALE NEWS ANCHOR ON TV:
In our business profile
tonight, Mariko Yashida.
A two-generation
passing of the torch
in the Yashida family...
as Mariko Yashida
takes the helm from
her grandfather,
who built this tech giant.
MARIKO ON TV: I know
it will always be the purpose
for a corporation
to make a profit...
but Yashida Industries
believes we can also work
with our community.
So, have you decided?
What?
Mariko says we can
go wherever we want.
Just say where.
What are you doing?
I'm your bodyguard.
So, where do
you want to go?
(SIGHS)
Uh...
Let's just start with up.
And then?
We'll see.
Interesting.
(EXHALES DEEPLY)
FEMALE ANNOUNCER ON TV:
With cutting edge technology,
and the world's
leading minds...
we are on the frontlines...
keeping you healthy,
keeping you safe.
Trask Industries.
Solving tomorrow's
problems, today.
I'll take the pat-down.
Opt out.
(METAL RATTLING)
(MACHINE BEEPING)
GUARD: You can go ahead, sir.
MAN: I'll wait.
(STRAINING)
What do you want?
There are dark forces,
Wolverine.
Human forces
building a weapon...
that could bring about
the end of our kind.
What do I want?
I want your help.
Why would I trust you?
You wouldn't.
(GASPS)
(PANTING)
Hello, Logan.
How is this possible?
As I told you
a long time ago...
you are not
the only one with gifts.
(SIGHS)